Emmet Family
Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
Jan 16, 1906 - To: Jane - From: Leslie - Subjects: Jane's father's funeral; Wilfrid
Jan 22, 1906 - To: Posie - From: Jane - Subjects: too lovely about Richie; old Mrs. Sargent died January 21
Jan 27, 1906 - To: Julia - From: Dev (in Dublin) - Subject: Alty Morgan
[Jan 31, 1906] - To: Julia - From: Jane - Subjects: Alida lunch at Hampton Court; poor Annie Lawley; Mary Dodge and Schreiner; Sargent back on Friday
Feb 2, 1906 - To: Granny - From: Robert (at Naval Academy)
[Feb 8, 1906] - To: Julia - From: Posie - Subjects: Bay painting Johnny Kane; Mrs. Townsend bought Beech Hill
Feb 9, 1906 - To: Julia - From: Jane - Subjects: Sargent upset; Jane does drawing of Roger Quilter
Feb 16, 1906 - To: Julia - From: Jane - Subjects: Sargent; quartet for Jane's departure; Percy Grainger; Alida to pose
Mar 1, 1906 - To: Jane - From: Julia - Subjects: Bobby Sherwood; Henry James
May 17, [1906] - To: Mrs. von Glehn - From: Julia - Subjects: Jane and Wilfrid sailed aboard the Philadelphia; Nelly will keep house for Lydia while she paints elsewhere
May 19, [1906] - To: Julia - From: Jane (aboard U.S.M.S. Philadelphia) - Subjects: off to Paris; Julia's hand
May [20], 1906 - To: Julia - From: Posie - Subjects: Cynthia has glasses; will move in 2 weeks; (drawing of view from new house)
May 24, 1906 - To: Julia - From: Jane - Subjects: Paris; Versailles; the Salon; Gosset
May 29, 1906 - To: Julia - From: Lydia - Subjects: will visit Sedgwicks; (drawing of a porch)
Jun 1, 1906 - To: Julia - From: Jane - Subjects: the Salon; Wilfrid has begun his painting of the Lord Mayor; Jane's lesson with Percy Grainger; Sargent wants them to go to Switzerland
Jun 9, 1906 - To: Jane - From: Posie - Subject: move to Skene Wood, Westport, Lake Champlain, N.Y.
Jun 27, 1906 - To: Julia - From: Jane - Subjects: Stanford White; Beigel; the Graingers; Roger Quilter; Gervase Eleves (singer and student of Beigel)
Jun 29, 1906 - To: Jane - From: Julia - Subject: Stanford White
Jun 30, 1906 - To: Julia - From: Jane (in London) - Subject: Stanford White
Jul 1, 1906 - To: Jane - From: Lydia - Subject: Stanford White; Saint-Gaudens
Jul 7, 1906 - To: Lydia - From: Bessie White - Subject: thanks for sympathy
[1906] - To: Posie - From: J.R.C.H. - Subject: Stanford White
Jul 11, 1906 - To: Julia - From: Jane - Subjects: Sargent; Peter to visit USA; Beigel and Eleves; Stanford White and McKim; Tom Hastings
Jul 14, 1906 - To: Julia - From: Ella - Subject: Bessie White
Jul 16, 1906 - To: Jane - From: Julia - Subject: Beigel
Jul 18, 1906 - To: Julia - From: Jane - Subject: Eleanor's baby born Jul 5
Jul 19, 1906 - To: Jane - From: Julia - Subject: Stanford White
Jul 23, 1906 - To: ? - From: Jane - Subject: dined with Scrivener chez Dodge; Dodge saw G.B. Shaw's Captain Brassbound's Conversion, starring Ellen Terry; Julia's hands; Jane to send drawings to the New English Art Club
Aug 3, 1906 - To: Jane - From: Julia - Subjects: Elizabeth (Betsy) had baby boy
Aug 3, 1906 - To: Julia - From: Jane (in Coutances, France) - Subjects: saw Katherine Hunter, Polly and Middleton; (drawing of Normandy figures)
Aug 7, [1906] - To: Julia - From: Jane (in Kent) - Subject: leave for Cherbourg on Saturday
Aug 13, 1906 - To: Julia - From: Jane (in Cherbourg) - Subjects: Uncle Willy died; wished they went with Sargent
Aug 18, 1906 - To: Julia - From: Ella - Subject: at Hyde Hall, Cooperstown, N.Y.
Aug 28, [1906] - To: Julia - From: Jane - Subject: visit of Henri Delacroix and Therese Lucien
Sep 11, [1906] - To: Julia - From: Jane - Subjects: Wilfrid and Arthur Blunt off painting; return to England on 25th; (drawing of a house and garden)
Sep 14, [1906] - To: Julia - From: Jane - Subject: has McKim arrived from Scotland?
Sep 17, 1906 - To: Julia - From: Jane - Subject: Bessie and Larry White in McKim's auto
Sep 18, 1906 - To: Jane - From: Julia - Subjects: Hearst running for governor of NY; Marie Kobbe's drawing of Maud's eldest boy; Mrs. Kobbe dying; Lydia trouble finding N.Y. studio; Alida lost her wedding ring
Sep 20, 1906 - To: Jane - From: Julia - Subject: Elizabeth's (Betsy's) blind baby died
[Sep 1906] - To: Jane - From: Posie - Subject: Lydia paints Mrs. Endicott Peabody
[1906] - To: Julia - From: Lydia - Subjects: Mrs. Peabody's portrait; the Joseph boys; Susie; Mrs. Whitney's bread; Dev and Ella arrive
Sep 24, 1906 - To: Jane - From: Lydia - Subjects: Mrs. Endicott Peabody's portrait; Mr. Kobbe died last Friday
Sep 25, 1906 - To: Julia - From: Jane - Subject: Leonard Borwick at home in Westbruton
Oct 2, [1906] - To: Julia - From: Jane - Subjects: Leonard Borwick leaves soon; Borwick had the Alma-Tademas and Miss Epps of Coco fame to dinner; Le Braz to visit U.S.
Oct 4, 1906 - To: Arthur Sherwood Sr. - From: Arthur Jr. - Subject: hazing at Harvard
Oct 9, [1906] - To: Lydia - From: Jane - Subjects: Leonard Borwick played his concert for them; Wilfrid's parents to visit on the 14th; Joachim concert soon
Oct 13, [1906] - To: Mr. Rockefeller - From: Posie - Subject: Happy New Year
Oct 16, [1906] - To: Julia - From: Jane - Subjects: George Moore died; Marian Curtis married; Leonard Borwick to London
Oct 26, [1906] - To: Julia - From: Jane - Subject: Maman and Papa (Wilfrid's parents) go home to Bromley
Nov 1, [1906] - To: Julia - From: Jane - Subjects: Gen. Palmer thrown from horse; Nelly Ward here; Dick Waterfield coming tomorrow; Leonard Borwick on Sunday; Holman Hunt
Nov 10, 1906 - To: Julia - From: Jane - Subjects: returned 8
Nov to 73 Cheyne Walk; Gen. Palmer paralyzed; Nelson Ward (their solicitor and descendant of Lord Nelson); Hearst's defeat
Nov 6, [1906] - To: Julia - From: Jane - Subjects: off to Cheyne Walk; Leslie's trusteeship
Nov 13, [1906] - To: Julia - From: Ella - Subject: Bessie White
Nov 13, 1906 - To: Julia - From: Jane - Subjects: Pauline's baby; Roger Quilter; Percy Grainger
Nov 16, 1906 - To: Julia - From: Jane - Subjects: Leonard Borwick; Holman Hunt exhibit; Colfax Gallery; Roger Quilter; Eleves; the Graingers; Sir Willy Ward
Nov 17, 1906 - To: Jane - From: Bay (at Barack Matif Farm, Salisbury, CT) - Subjects: Mary Foote; Bay painted Forbes family; Leslie is ill; Stanford's portrait
Nov 21, 1906 - To: Lydia - From: Jane - Subject: Joachim concerts
Dec 1, 1906 - To: Jane - From: Lydia - Subjects: Zeb and Maria engaged; Florence's baby
Dec 1, 1906 - To: Posie - From: Arthur Jr. (in Boston) - Subject: Dev, Ella, and Mrs. Stanford White
[Dec 1, 1906] - To: Julia - From: Posie - Subject: Anne Hyde Clarke
Dec 4, 1906 - To: Julia - From: Jane - Subjects: Jane to visit soon; studio looks like a chapel; Leonard Borwick; Rachel here for Joachim concert
Dec 4, 1906 - To: Jane - From: Julia - Subject: Hearst/Hughes election
[1906] - To: Julia - From: Jane - Subjects: Arthur Jr. lazy at college; Dick has broken engagement to Sally Flagg; Mr. Whitehead pleased about Zeb and Maria; Posie cartoons of B. Cochran and little Mary Ladenburg; Roger Quilter; Wilfrid May exhibit at Carfax's Gallery
Dec 12, [1906] - To: Jane - From: Julia - Subjects: church glass; book by H.G. Wells
Dec 12, 1906 - To: Julia - From: Jane - Subjects: Dennis O'Sullivan sang; the Corrigans; Shamus O'Brien (Sargent's friend)
Dec 14,1906 - To: Lydia - From: Jane - Subjects: Jane missed Sargent dinner; Cohen dinner; Wilfrid's stained glass window
Dec 15,1906 - To: Julia - From: Jane - Subjects: Wilfrid's window has been installed; will visit Speyers
Dec 18, 1906 - To: Julia - From: Jane - Subjects: Sunday at Speyers; Sargent; Alma Harrison; Dennis O'Sullivan; Peter (Harrison?) still in Colorado; Leonard Borwick; Beigel
Dec 21, 1906 - To: Julia - From: Jane - Subjects: tea with Sargent's sister, Violet Ormond; Percy Grainger is moving; Leonard Borwick; Mabel leaves
Jan 7, 1907 - To: Jane - From: Lydia - Subjects: Lydia's exhibition; Peebles' photo; Alida's portrait
Jan 8, 1907 - To: Jane - From: Posie - Subjects: Arthur Jr. on probation;Louis Strong can't close Hyde Hall
Jan 10, 1907 - To: Julia - From: Jane - Subject: Sargent painting Mrs. Waldorf Astor; Jane hasn't gotten Sargent painting yet; Gibson painting in Paris; deaths of Chris and Reggie Balfour
Jan 11, 1907 - To: Julia - From: Jane - Subjects: Lady Constance MacKenzie is now Stewart-Richardson; Sir William Richmond (R.A.)
Jan 14, 1907 - To: Julia - From: Jane - Subjects: dinner party with Sargent, Violet Ormond, Henry Tonks, and Percy Grainger; Jane hopes to see Henry James
Jan 15, 1907 - To: Julia - From: Dev (in London) - Subjects: Jane took Ella to see Lady Constance MacKenzie in a diving competition; Jane did a drawing of MacKenzie yesterday; description of travels
Jan 20, 1907 - To: Jane - From: Lydia - Subject: Gordon King's children
Jan 23, 1907 - To: Lydia - From: Jane (Lamb House, Rye, England) - Subject: Henry James
Jan 29, 1907 - To: Julia - From: Jane (73 Cheyne Walk) - Subjects: Henry James' nephew Billy studying painting in Paris; Thaw trial; Sargent and (sister) Emily Sargent; Gen. Palmer is well; Robert Allerton
Jan 31, 1907 - To: Julia - From: Jane - Subject: Henry James
Feb 2, 1907 - To: Julia - From: Jane - Subjects: Henry James; Sargent
Feb 5, 1907 - To: Julia - From: Jane - Subjects: Wilfrid's painting of Diana; Henry James and Sargent; (diagram of shape of canvas)
Feb 10, [1907] - To: Jane - From: Lydia - Subjects: Susie's concert tomorrow; Julia; Thaw and Stanford White; Bessie White
Feb 13, 1907 - To: Julia - From: Jane - Subjects: to Cambridge to see Louis in Moliere; Roger Quilter ill Feb 12, 1907] - To: Julia - From: Posie (in Baltimore) - Subjects: the Bacons, Robert Bacon; Alice Roosevelt
Feb 15, 1907 - To: Jane - From: Julia - Subjects: Posie to go to Washington, D.C. on Monday
Feb 16, 1907 - To: Julia - From: Jane - Subject: Dickie Borie
Feb 19, 1907 - To: Jane - From: Julia - Subjects: Henry James drawing; new President keeps Bob Bacon on tenter hooks
Feb 20, 1907 - To: Julia - From: Jane - Subjects: Borwick's concert; Henry James letter
Feb 21, 1907 - To: Jane - From: Julia - Subject: Thaw trial
Feb 23, 1907 - To: Julia - From: Jane - Subject: Max Beerbohm (half-brother of Beerbohm Tree)
Feb 28, 1907 - To: Julia - From: Posie - Subjects: Bob Bacon and the President; Bobby Sherwood's poem Hiawatha
Mar 5, 1907 - To: Julia - From: Jane - Subjects: Roger Quilter's health is better; Louis lessons with Beigel; Wilfrid's father ill
Mar 9, 1907 - To: Julia - From: Jane - Subjects: Wilfrid finishing portrait of Jane; Le Braz's little girls; Henry James book
Mar 9, 1907 - To: Jane - From: Lydia - Subjects: Thaw trial; Alida ill; Temple's portrait
Mar 16, 1907 - To: Julia - From: Jane - Subjects: Roger Quilter; Alfred Parsons (collector); Gervase Elewes; Jane does drawing of Lady Quilter
May 4, 1907 - To: Nelly - From: G. Hyde Clarke (in Cooperstown, New York) - Subjects: "Skene" was a patent name for the land in Westport
May 26, 1907 - To: Julia - From: Jane (aboard U.S.M.S. Philadelphia) - Subjects: leaves New York; Alida's friend Niels Gron on board; Julia's hand
Jun 1, 1907 - To: Julia - From: Jane (aboard U.S.M.S. Philadelphia) - Subject: Horton Pope; Gen. McCoskry Butt
Jun 13, 1907 - To: Jane - From: Julia - Subjects: Lydia at home this month; Zeb and Maria's wedding; (9 photographs of wedding)
Jun 14, 1907 - To: Julia - From: Jane - Subjects: Percy Grainger recital; Robert Allerton; Mrs. Phelps at wedding; Wilfrid takes his parents to Walmer on Monday
Jun 18, 1907 - To: Julia - From: Jane - Subjects: Wilfrid painting Banster's wife; Wilfrid's father too ill to travel; Beigel; Lady Bective; Robert Hichens (writer); Jane will do Niels Gron's portrait
Jun 25, 1907 - To: Julia - From: Jane - Subjects: Sargent's sisters; Sargent wants them to go to Switzerland; description of wedding photos; Henry Tonks; Mrs. Ormond Steer
Jun 29, 1907 - To: Julia - From: Wilfrid - Subjects: another window commission--decoration of Robert Allerton's house; how is Rand; may go to Switzerland; the Quilters on Sunday
Jul 4, 1907 - To: Julia - From: Jane - Subjects: Margaret Aldrich; ink eradicator
Jul 4, [1907] - To: Posie - From: Julia - Subjects: what Posie suffered Tuesday; letter from Aunt July
Jul 5, 1907 - To: Jane - From: Julia - Subjects: Cynthia's appendix operation; Ellen Terry's book
Jul 5, 1907 - To: Jane - From: Lydia - Subjects: to Stockbridge; thanks for easel ring
Jul 6, 1907 - To: Julia - From: Jane - Subjects: suffrage meeting; Sir Willy Ward; Lady Scott Moverieff; Julia Culp (singer); drawing of Niels Gron; off to Walmer
Jul 7, 1907 - To: Jane - From: Julia - Subjects: Albert Stickney and Kate Lapsley engaged
Jul 9, 1907 - To: Julia - From: Jane - Subjects: Grace Carter; Anne Hyde; Wilfrid paints Lady Ed____; Penshurst to see Wilfrid's windows
Jul 17, 1907 - To: Posie - From: Jane - Subjects: Switzerland plans with Sargent; Sargent will paint no more portraits
Jul 17, 1907 - To: Julia - From: Jane - Subjects: Stanley Clarke's daughter's engagement; Lady Constance back from Africa
Jul 22, 1907 - To: Julia - From: Jane - Subject: the Quilters
Jul 25, 1907 - To: Rosina (Posie?) - From: Mary G. Clarke (at Hyde Hall, Cooperstown, New York) - Subject: thanks for the visit to Skene Wood
Aug 3, 1907 - To: Julia - From: Jane (in France) - Subject: Wilfrid is now a Societaire of Society of Beaux Arts
Aug 3, 1907 - To: Jane - From: Lydia - Subject: Edith Barrett
Aug 5, 1907 - To: Julia - From: Jane - Subject: Sargent's already in Switzerland
Aug 9, 1907 - To: Julia - From: Posie - Subject: Uncle Frank Fiske's death; the play
Aug 9, 1907 - To: Lydia - From: Jane - Subjects: arrived last night; Sargent and the Ormonds
Aug 13, 1907 - To: Julia - From: Jane - Subjects: Julia's hand better; Sargent and the Ormonds
Aug 16, 1907 - To: Julia - From: Jane - Subject: the children's appendix operations
Aug 20, 1907 - To: Julia - From: Jane (in Switzerland) - Subject: Sargent hasn't done Wilfrid's portrait yet
[Aug 23, 1907] - To: Jane - From: Julia - Subject: Anne engaged to broker, Arthur Osgood Choate
Aug 25, 1907 - To: Julia - From: Jane (in Switzerland) - Subjects: ex-Queen Margherita of Italy for lunch;Sargent
Aug 27, 1907 - To: Jane - From: Julia - Subject: Mrs. von Glehn's shock
Aug 30, 1907 - To: Julia - From: Jane - Subject: Mr. Hamill's death Aug 1907] - To: Julia - From: Lydia - Subject: neighborhood fair
Sep 3, 1907 - To: Wilfrid - From: Posie - Subject: can Sargent paint Jane?
Sep 7, 1907 - To: Jane - From: Lydia - Subjects: Herman Kobbe's Beaux Arts friend Adler; Helen Peabody
Sep 11, 1907 - To: Julia - From: Jane (in Florence) - Subject: description of travels
Sept 13, [1907] - To: Helene - From: Julia - Subjects: Herman Kobbe; Egerton is 5 months old; Julia's hand Sept 13, 1907 - To: Jane - From: Julia - Subjects: Louis Metcalfe lived in Lydia's studio this summer
Sep 20, 1907 - To: Jane - From: Julia - Subject: Bobby Sherwood looks weak on his long legs
Sep 24, 1907 - To: Julia - From: Jane (in Frascati) - Subjects: Sargent; Eliza Wedgewood; Anne and Reddie Choate; travels to Turin, Bologna, Florence, Siena, Perugia, Assisi, Narvi, Frascoti, and Rome; (includes an admission ticket to Villa Torlonia in Frascati, 14 Sep 1907)
Oct 6, 1907 - To: Lydia - From: Jane (in Frascati) - Subject: Sargent doing drawing of Jane
Oct 14, 1907 - To: Julia - From: Jane (in Frascati) - Subjects: Sargent and Wilfrid to Rome; Lady Helen Vincent; Wilfrid's father has fever
Oct 18, 1907 - To: Jane - From: Lydia - Subject: Anne's wedding
Oct 18, 1907 - To: Jane - From: Julia - Subjects: Lydia looking for a studio; Peabody portrait
Oct 18, 1907] - To: Julia - From: Lydia - Subject: Bobby Sherwood's knee
Oct 21, 1907 - To: Jane - From: Russell - Subject: cotillion
Oct 21, 1907 - To: Jane - From: Lydia - Subjects: Susie and Lilli (Metcalfe) sailing to Paris
Jan 20; Lydia wants Susie to sing at Sargent's in London; Alida pregnant
Oct 23, 1907 - To: Jane - From: Julia - Subject: Lydia has studio
Nov 1, 1907 - To: Jane - From: Julia - Subjects: Lilli and Mary Foote; Dorothy Moran; Elizabeth Biddle
Nov 3, 1907 - To: Jane - From: Julia - Subjects: Bobby Sherwood sings "Give My Regards to Broadway"; Arthur Sherwood has lost every cent--Knickerbocker Trust failed
[Nov 1907] - To: Julia - From: Posie - Subjects: Bobby Sherwood's entertainment wonderful; Cynthia to Morgan's ball
[Nov 1907] - To: Julia - From: Posie - Subjects: stock market closed; (drawing of a bush covered for winter)
Nov 7, 1907 - To: Lydia - From: Jane - Subjects: Hyde Hall wedding; Beigel; Eleanor's baby; Sargent; Roger Quilter
Nov 14, 1907 - To: Jane - From: Lydia - Subjects: Peggy Keogh's picture; McKim;Mary Foote copy of Saint-Gaudens work
Nov 15, 1907 - To: Jane - From: Julia - Subjects: Arthur Sherwood all right; Kitty's baby may be named Bridgit (eventually named Mary); Mrs. Phelps
Nov 20, 1907 - To: Julia - From: Jane (in Rome) - Subjects: Sargent's picture of them; too bad about Mr. Barney
Nov 22, 1907 - To: Jane - From: Lydia (in Plainfield) - Subjects: Susie's concert; Crabbe the baritone; Cecilia Beaux; Lydia's portraits of Peggy and of Jack Beresford
Nov 26, 1907 - To: Jane - From: Julia - Subject: (photographs of Bobby and Rosamond Sherwood at Skene Wood)
Dec 7, 1907 - To: Julia - From: Jane (at Cheyne Walk) - Subject: just arrived home
Dec 11, 1907 - To: Julia - From: Jane - Subject: Sargent bought Wilfrid's watercolors
Dec 13, 1907 - To: Jane - From: Julia - Subject: Lydia's portrait of Agassig girls
Dec 17, 1907 - To: Julia - From: Jane - Subjects: the little Ormonds and Nelly in studio; Eliza Wedgewood to spend week wth Emily Sargent; Beigel and Dickie Borie to dinner
Dec 19, 1907 - To: Jane - From: Julia - Subject: Temple and Alida's baby Egerton died
Dec 20, [1907] - To: Jane - From: Lydia - Subjects: Egerton's funeral; Lydia's Agassiz painting won $200 Proctor prize
Dec 30, 1907 - To: Julia - From: Jane - Subject: dinner party with Sargent, Emily Sargent, Eliza Wedgewood, and Percy Grainger
Jan 2, 1908 - To: Jane - From: Alida - Subject: Alida will sail on Jan 15 to Europe
Jan 8, 1908 - To: Julia - From: Jane - Subjects: Henry Tonks to dinner; Mrs. Barnard; Nelly Ward; Wilfrid's Carfax show
Jan 11, 1908 - To: Julia - From: Ella - Subjects: back in Dublin; friend Christopher La Touche
Jan 17, 1908 - To: Julia - From: Jane - Subject: Lady Constance to pose for Wilfrid
Jan 21, 1908 - To: Julia - From: Jane - Subjects: Quilter's music dedicated to Jane; Sunday was spent at Rye with cousin Henry James
Jan 29, 1908 - To: Julia - From: Ella - Subjects: Sir Horace Plunkett to dinner; Bessie and Larry White in Egypt
Jan 31, 1908 - To: Jane - From: Julia - Subjects: Temple and Alida's trip to Germany; Bessie White
Feb 1, 1908 - To: Julia - From: Jane - Subjects: Susie singing engagement; Julia's eye;Leonard Borwick; Debussy in person
Feb 4, 1908 - To: Julia - From: Jane - Subjects: Susie's concert in Paris; Sir Charles Wyndham and Mary Moore in The Mollusc--Henry James doesn't like the play; dinner with actors after; Mlle. Nathalie Henzen ("Tante Tata") is older sister of Tante Olga, Uncle Gabriel's wife--they are daughters of Henzen the Russian exile
Feb 12, 1908 - To: Julia - From: Jane - Subjects: Eliza's on Sunday; Cynthia Charteris; Tony De Navarro
Feb 17, 1908 - To: Jane - From: Julia - Subject: Bessie and Monod
Feb 19, 1908 - To: Julia - From: Jane - Subjects: Mancini the Italian "crazy" painter; Wilfrid's opening yesterday; portrait of Lady Constance; costume ball tomorrow; May Coles, sister Mrs. Arthur Davis (Sylvia Dumaurier)--J.M. Barrie wrote Peter Pan for Davis children; Tom Balfour married yesterday
Feb 28, 1908 - To: Jane - From: Lydia - Subjects: cousin Janey broke leg; Cynthia Charteris' portrait
Feb 29, 1908 - To: Julia - From: Jane - Subjects: costume ball; Emily and Violet Sargent; Lady Constance's portrait; Jane's drawing of Michael Davis and may do portrait of J.M. Barrie; Spanish guitarists at Sargent's
Feb 29, 1908 - To: Julia - From: Jane - Subjects: Beigel; Susie sang
Mar 7, 1908 - To: Julia - From: Jane - Subjects: Susie's concert; Bernard Shaw lecture; Eliza Wells Holt; Leonard Borwick
Mar 10, 1908 - To: Julia - From: Jane - Subjects: Kitty's operation; Wilfrid's parents got a stove
Mar 17, 1908 - To: Julia - From: Jane - Subjects: Mrs. Hunter; Mrs. Ramney (singer); Kob; Wilfrid in Paris for his exhibition
Mar 22, 1908 - To: Julia - From: Jane - Subjects: Jane to Paris tomorrow; invitation to Cliveden by Astors with Sargent; Susie Metcalfe's command performance; Old Willy Waldorf; (drawing of stove)
Mar 26, 1908 - To: Lydia - From: Ella - Subject: Julia's eyes
Jun 2, 1908 - To: Julia - From: Jane - Subjects: Leonard Borwick; Cynthia Charteris visiting; Lord Northbourne lunch; Bessie Dufais' death
Jun 5, [1908] - To: Julia - From: Jane - Subjects: Wilfrid's parents come at last; Charles Rist visits (Edouard's brother, Germaine's husband, Uncle Gabriel's son-in-law); Arthur at Harvard; Mr. Kobbe's death; Leonard Borwick
Aug 11, 1908 - To: Lydia - From: Jane - Subjects: Wilfrid to stay at "Stanway" the Elchoes' place; Wilfrid painting another portrait of Cynthia Charteris; Louis' friend Walter Cohen
Aug 14, 1908 - To: Lydia - From: Mrs. Dufais - Subjects: Sargent; Eliza; Wilfrid's portrait of Cynthia (Charteris)
Aug 14, 1908 - To: Julia - From: Jane - Subject: lunching with Millets
Aug 18, 1908] - To: Julia - From: Posie - Subject: (drawing of Posie being thrown from a horse)
Aug 21, 1908 - To: Jane - From: Lydia - Subjects: Lydia's portrait of Nite; Lydia can't paint Mrs. French until Monday; medical advice
Aug 31, [1908] - To: Jane - From: Lydia - Subject: Julia ill
Sep 18, 1908 - To: Jane - From: Lydia - Subjects: Lydia to paint Martha Bacon; put Mrs. French off; Julia faint and sweating
Sep 24, 1908 - To: Jane - From: Lydia - Subject: Russell Peabody died [Julia Pierson Colt Emmet died September 26, 1908]
Oct 24, 1908 - To: Jane - From: Emily Sargent(in Spain) - Subjects: Jane's dear invalid released from suffering; Sargent
Apr 15, 1909 - To: Lydia - From: National Academy of Design - Subject: associate membership notice
Jun 7, [1909] - To: Jane - From: Lydia - Subjects: Mary Foote; Lydia's mastectomy (?)
Jun 22, [1909] - To: Jane - From: Lydia - Subjects: Lydia's recovery; Crowninshield appointed head of McKim's architectural school in Rome; Mary Foote
Aug 13, [1909] - To: Posie - From: Arthur Sr. (in Seattle) - Subject: Cynthia engaged to Jim Townsend
Aug 28, 1909 - To: Jane - From: Lydia - Subject: Cynthia's wedding described
Sep 2, 1909 - To: Jane - From: Lydia - Subjects: the Choates; sorry Jane not in Switzerland longer
Sep 1909 Von Glehn receipt from Venice, Italy]
Sep 17, 1909 - To: Jane - From: Lydia - Subjects: Stockbridge Casino art benefit including works by French, Crowninshield, Matilda [Brownell?], and Morse's son
Sep 20, 1909 - To: Jane - From: Lydia - Subjects: Bobby Sherwood and the Fair; old Mr. Griswold died; McKim's death; little Goddard Iselin died
[Sep 1909] - To: Lydia - From: Posie - Subjects: Ilse's engagement to Broderotti; Archer Huntington; Bobby S. and the Fair
[Sep 1909] - To: Nelly - From: Bobby Sherwood - Subject: date of the Fair
Sep 27, 1909 - To: Lydia - From: Ella - Subjects: McKim; historical pageant
[1909] - To: Lydia - From: Nelly - Subject: Mary Foote about a studio
Oct 5, 1909 - To: Jane - From: Lydia - Subjects: Jane in Venice or Corfu; Mrs. Hill's portrait
Oct 6, 1909 - To: Lydia - From: Posie - Subjects: Arthur in hospital; Arthur's classmate is president of Harvard
Oct 25, 1909 - To: Jane - From: Posie - Subjects: Lydia working on Phipps picture; Lydia dissapointed with painting of Morris children
Nov 19, [1909] - To: Jane - From: Lydia - Subjects: Phipps picture; MacMonnies
Dec 26, 1909 - To: Jane - From: Posie - Subjects: Wilfrid's mother ("Maman"); Jim's blood poisoning; Cynthia's move to Pennsylvania; Frederic Remington's death
Oct 7, 1910 - To: Jane - From: Posie - Subjects: Cynthia's engagement ring; Herbert Brown (architect) will do Woodland for Marjorie